<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Asahi Linux</title><link>https://asahilinux.org/</link><description>Recent content on Asahi Linux</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 12:04:00 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://asahilinux.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Asahi Progress Report: January / February 2021</title><link>https://asahilinux.org/2021/03/asahi-progress-report-january-/-february-2021/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 12:04:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://asahilinux.org/2021/03/asahi-progress-report-january-/-february-2021/</guid><description>Welcome to the first Asahi Linux Progress Report! In this series we&amp;rsquo;ll be taking a page from the Dolphin playbook and giving you monthly updates on the progress of the project.
Bringing up support for a new system-on-chip on Linux is no small task! I hope this series will be educational to everyone and give you a glimpse of the behind-the-scenes work that goes into making Linux work on a brand new device.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://asahilinux.org/about/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 20:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://asahilinux.org/about/</guid><description>About Asahi Linux Asahi Linux is a project and community with the goal of porting Linux to Apple Silicon Macs, starting with the 2020 M1 Mac Mini, MacBook Air, and MacBook Pro.
Our goal is not just to make Linux run on these machines but to polish it to the point where it can be used as a daily OS. Doing this requires a tremendous amount of work, as Apple Silicon is an entirely undocumented platform.</description></item><item><title>Code of Conduct</title><link>https://asahilinux.org/code-of-conduct/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 20:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://asahilinux.org/code-of-conduct/</guid><description>Asahi Linux Code of Conduct Like many Open Source projects and the greater FLOSS community, Asahi Linux is a collaborative open source community comprised of a diverse group of contributors and users from around the globe. We find the contributions, collaborations, and mentorships within our community to be the essential lifeblood of our project and appreciate the efforts of those who participate to nurture and grow those, and all other aspects of our community.</description></item><item><title>Community</title><link>https://asahilinux.org/community/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 20:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://asahilinux.org/community/</guid><description>Community If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in the project, you&amp;rsquo;re welcome to drop by! Check out ways in which you can contribute.
Please rememeber that all community members are expected to abide by our Code of Conduct.
IRC Most development and project discussion takes place on IRC. We have several channels on the Freenode IRC network:
#asahi [logs 路 matrix] - General project discussion #asahi-dev [logs 路 matrix] - Development discussion #asahi-re [logs 路 matrix] - Reverse engineering (hardware/firmware interfaces/etc) #asahi-gpu [logs 路 matrix] - GPU reverse engineering and development Even if you don&amp;rsquo;t plan to speak, feel free to join and idle in the above channels if you&amp;rsquo;d like to follow the discussion.</description></item><item><title>Contribute</title><link>https://asahilinux.org/contribute/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 20:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://asahilinux.org/contribute/</guid><description>Contribute Asahi Linux is an open source project, and it would not be possible without the support of the community. We encourage contributors of all skill sets and backgrounds!
All contributors are expected to abide by our Code of Conduct and our Copyright and Reverse Engineering policy.
New to this kind of thing? Are you interested in this kind of project, but you&amp;rsquo;ve never worked on something like this before? We were all like that at one point!</description></item><item><title>Copyright &amp; Reverse Engineering</title><link>https://asahilinux.org/copyright/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 20:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://asahilinux.org/copyright/</guid><description>Copyright policy Asahi Linux is an open source project, and all contributions must follow the appropriate open source licenses.
These contribution rules are particularly important for code that is to be upstreamed into other projects, to maintain a clean paper trail of the licensing.
Licensing Code developed for Asahi Linux itself should be licensed under a permissive license that allows other projects to take advantage of the code without running into license compatibility problems.</description></item><item><title>Support</title><link>https://asahilinux.org/support/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 20:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://asahilinux.org/support/</guid><description>Support Asahi Linux Asahi Linux was started by marcan as a Patreon-funded project, and he is currently aiming to raise enough pledges to allow him to work on Asahi Linux full-time on both Patreon and GitHub sponsors. If you would like to contribute to this cause financially, head over to the patreon campaign or the GitHub sponsors page. To make a one-time donation or for other arrangements, please contact marcan directly.</description></item></channel></rss>