<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on Asahi Linux</title><link>https://asahilinux.org/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on Asahi Linux</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 23:50:00 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://asahilinux.org/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Paving the Road to Vulkan on Asahi Linux</title><link>https://asahilinux.org/2023/03/road-to-vulkan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 23:50:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://asahilinux.org/2023/03/road-to-vulkan/</guid><description>Hello everyone, Asahi Lina here!✨
As you probably know, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working together with the rest of the Asahi Linux team on open source GPU drivers for Apple Silicon platforms. It&amp;rsquo;s been a wild ride! Just at the end of last year we released the first version of our drivers, after many months of reverse engineering and development. But that was only the beginning&amp;hellip;
Today we&amp;rsquo;re releasing a big update to our GPU drivers for Asahi Linux, so I wanted to talk to you about what we&amp;rsquo;ve been working on since then, and what&amp;rsquo;s next!</description></item><item><title>Apple GPU drivers now in Asahi Linux</title><link>https://asahilinux.org/2022/12/gpu-drivers-now-in-asahi-linux/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 14:50:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://asahilinux.org/2022/12/gpu-drivers-now-in-asahi-linux/</guid><description>Hello everyone! We&amp;rsquo;re excited to announce our first public Apple Silicon GPU driver release!
We&amp;rsquo;ve been working hard over the past two years to bring this new driver to everyone, and we&amp;rsquo;re really proud to finally be here. This is still an alpha driver, but it&amp;rsquo;s already good enough to run a smooth desktop experience and some games.
Read on to find out more about the state of things today, how to install it (it&amp;rsquo;s an opt-in package), and how to report bugs!</description></item><item><title>Tales of the M1 GPU</title><link>https://asahilinux.org/2022/11/tales-of-the-m1-gpu/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 23:50:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://asahilinux.org/2022/11/tales-of-the-m1-gpu/</guid><description>Hello everyone, Asahi Lina here!✨
marcan asked me to write an article about the M1 GPU, so here we are~! It&amp;rsquo;s been a long road over the past few months and there&amp;rsquo;s a lot to cover, so I hope you enjoy it!
What&amp;rsquo;s a GPU? You probably know what a GPU is, but do you know how they work under the hood? Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look! Almost all modern GPUs have the same main components:</description></item><item><title>Updates galore! November 2022 Progress Report</title><link>https://asahilinux.org/2022/11/november-2022-report/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 23:50:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://asahilinux.org/2022/11/november-2022-report/</guid><description>Time for another overdue progress report! This month&amp;rsquo;s update is packed with new hardware support, new features, and fixes for longstanding pain points, as well as a new bleeding-edge kernel branch with long-awaited support for suspend and the display controller!
If you&amp;rsquo;re new to Asahi Linux, check out our previous release announcement for installation instructions and general information.
USB3, Chapter 1 Until now, Asahi Linux has only supported USB2 on the Thunderbolt ports.</description></item><item><title>M2 is here! July 2022 Release &amp; Progress Report</title><link>https://asahilinux.org/2022/07/july-2022-release/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://asahilinux.org/2022/07/july-2022-release/</guid><description>Welcome to another long overdue progress report! As usual, things have been busier than expected… and we have some big news! We’ve just released a new Asahi Linux update with Mac Studio, Bluetooth, and M2 support!
If you&amp;rsquo;re new to Asahi Linux, check out our previous release announcement for installation instructions and general information.
Mac Studio joins the family When the Mac Studio was announced, we set to work making the new M1 Ultra work with Asahi Linux.</description></item><item><title>The first Asahi Linux Alpha Release is here!</title><link>https://asahilinux.org/2022/03/asahi-linux-alpha-release/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 23:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asahilinux.org/2022/03/asahi-linux-alpha-release/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a long while since we updated the blog! Truth be told, we wanted to write a couple more progress reports, but there was always &amp;ldquo;one more thing&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip; So, instead, we decided to take the plunge and publish the first public alpha release of the Asahi Linux reference distribution!
We&amp;rsquo;re really excited to finally take this step and start bringing Linux on Apple Silicon to everyone. This is only the beginning, and things will move even more quickly going forward!</description></item><item><title>Progress Report: October-November 2021</title><link>https://asahilinux.org/2021/12/progress-report-oct-nov-2021/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://asahilinux.org/2021/12/progress-report-oct-nov-2021/</guid><description>Whoops, things got so busy we ended up skipping a month! A lot has been going on in kernel land over the past couple of months, so we hope you enjoy this combined October-November progress report!
M1 Pro/Max joins the family At the end of October, Apple launched the next generation of Apple Silicon: M1 Pro and M1 Max. We got right to work on supporting these new machines, and after just a few days of work we were able to bring up Asahi Linux on them up to feature parity with the M1 machines!</description></item><item><title>Progress Report: September 2021</title><link>https://asahilinux.org/2021/10/progress-report-september-2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 01:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://asahilinux.org/2021/10/progress-report-september-2021/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a busy month! We&amp;rsquo;ve had a lot of movement in kernel land, as well as some tooling improvements and reverse engineering sessions. At this point, Asahi Linux is usable as a basic Linux desktop (without GPU acceleration)! The ground had been shifting until now, but we&amp;rsquo;re seeing drivers settle down. Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at what&amp;rsquo;s been going on.
Linux drivers galore Earlier this year we saw the absolute lowest level drivers being merged into the kernel.</description></item><item><title>Progress Report: August 2021</title><link>https://asahilinux.org/2021/08/progress-report-august-2021/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 15:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://asahilinux.org/2021/08/progress-report-august-2021/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a long time since the last update! In all honesty, the first Progress Report set the bar a little bit too high, and I found it difficult to sit down and put together monthly reports that would do it justice. So, going forward, we&amp;rsquo;re going to be providing shorter-form updates while striving to keep a monthly schedule.
That said, a lot has happened in the past few months, so strap in for a bigger update this time!</description></item><item><title>Progress Report: January / February 2021</title><link>https://asahilinux.org/2021/03/progress-report-january-february-2021/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 12:04:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://asahilinux.org/2021/03/progress-report-january-february-2021/</guid><description>Welcome to the first Asahi Linux Progress Report! In this series we&amp;rsquo;ll be taking a page from the Dolphin playbook and giving you monthly updates on the progress of the project.
Bringing up support for a new system-on-chip on Linux is no small task! I hope this series will be educational to everyone and give you a glimpse of the behind-the-scenes work that goes into making Linux work on a brand new device.</description></item></channel></rss>